远鉴字幕组\h\h翻译
CSEG克隆字幕提取组\h\h提取制作
\h\h翻译\h\h
Ronronner
Alina
Brook想养猫
chlsyzzz
\h\h翻译\h\h
Florrie
耿耿Valya
会飞的小丫
Jamxii
\h\h翻译\h\h
刘开开
如意小鱼
小基
阳小羊
\h\h翻译\h\h
一个大窝瓜
芝麻不要开门
Freddie爱咳嗽
猴ing
\h\h翻译\h\h
海棠酒满
静默のShawn
LaurelW
Sleeplessclaire
\h\h翻译\h\h
维克多查
张克拉嗑拉啦
\h\h校对\h\h
JulianVaughn
\h\h监制\h\h
\h\h提取\h\h
可乐@CESG
本字幕由CSEG克隆字幕提取组提取分享  仅供学习交流之用  禁止压制  禁止删除字幕组及CSEG署名
欢迎关注新浪微博、微信公众号：CSEG克隆字幕提取组
可怜的东西
爸
Ba.
爸 爸
Ba! Ba!
爸 爸 爸
Ba, ba, ba.
-拜拜  -爸爸
- Bye. - Ba, ba.
这里是一堆内脏 没有来自大脑的自我意识
A pile of organs without the spark of self from a brain...
也没有来自心脏的供血
or the pump of blood from a heart.
它们就只是屠夫的一顿周日午餐罢了
Just a butcher's tray for a Sunday lunch.
那么我问你们 谁想将这些内脏重新组合到一起
Now, who would like to reconstruct the organs?
而谁又能区分人类与动物 人与动物真的有区别吗
And who can tell human from animal, if there is a difference?
回答呀
Come, come.
你们小时候都玩过拼图 对吧
You did puzzles as children, did you not?
不知道是不是只有我这么想
Is it just me,
但你们不觉得 要集中精神听这个怪物讲话 实在太难了吗
or is it devilishly hard to concentrate when the monster's talking?
他是个非常优秀的外科医生
He is an extraordinary surgeon.
他的研究极具开创性 他父亲建立了这所学校
His research is groundbreaking. His father founded this place.
你是不是误以为你也能加入我们的谈话马 克斯·麦克坎多斯
Have you mistaken yourself as included in this conversation, Max McCandles?
就算你的座位与我们相邻也不代表你可以加入我们的谈话
Your physical proximity to us does not make it so.
滚开 老东西 买件西装穿吧
Fuck off, old pal. Get yourself a suit.
你真的认为肝脏应该放在这里吗 先生
You really think that's where the liver goes, sir?
将内脏放回去的目的是什么呢 先生
Can I ask what is the purpose of putting them back in, sir?
让我开心
My amusement.
马克斯·麦克坎多斯先生
Mr. Max McCandles!
这堂课结束后来找我
Walk with me at the end of the lesson.
你的论文
Your paper.
您觉得还行吗 先生
You liked it, sir?
你的论文展现出 一个思想符合常规的人为了仅仅触及平庸就下了很多功夫
It showed signs of a conventional mind straining hard to almost touch mediocrity.
-谢谢您  -我需要一个人助手来参与一个项目
- Thank you. - I need someone. An assistant on a project.
我非常乐意
I would love to.
-你有信仰吗  -我相信古德
- Are you a religious man? - I believe in God.
古德温的昵称"God"意为古德
-你指的是我 还是上帝  -您真幽默 您常被称为...
- Me or the deity? - Humorous, as you're often known as the...
那只是我自己开的玩笑
It is a joke of my own making.
我不需要旁人解释给我自己听
I do not need it explicated for me.
这是恶魔的成果
The very devil's work.
您考虑过蓄胡子吗 先生
Have you thought of growing a beard, sir?
我会看起来像一条戴着领带的大狗
I look like a big dog in a cravat.
小孩们喜欢狗
Kids like dogs.
您还没说是什么工作
This job.
啊对 来
Yes. Come.
天 天
God! God.
天啊
God.
-你好  -你好
- Hello. - Hello.
贝拉 这是麦克坎多斯先生
Bella, this is Mr. McCandles.
你好 贝拉
Hello, Bella.
-虚也  -血
- Bud. - Blood.
-血  -太棒了
- Blood. - Marvelous.
我没事 我没事
I'm fine. I'm fine.
多漂亮的智障啊
What a very pretty retard.
她大脑受了外伤
She suffered a brain injury.
我修复了她
I repaired it.
她的心理年龄和她的身体并不同步
Her mental age and her body are not quite synchronized.
她还在学习语言 她在飞速进步
Language is coming. She is progressing at an accelerated pace.
她美极了
She is stunning.
我需要事无巨细地记录下她的进步
I need to meticulously note her progression.
你愿意帮我记录吗
You will do this for me?
这是我的荣幸
It would be my honor.
咿
Wee!
呀
是的 这很令人激动 贝拉
Yes. It is exciting, Bella.
-呀  -我觉得她在
"Wee." I believe she's doing...
普瑞姆女士
Mrs. Prim!
咿
Wee.
你不喜欢腌鱼吗
Do you not like kippers?
呃 我其实挺喜欢
I am quite partial to them, actually.
我觉得腌鱼很适合早上吃
I find them to be nice in the morning...
贝拉也切
Bella cut, too?
贝拉只能切死的
Just dead ones for Bella.
只能死的
Just dead.
只能切死人
吧唧 吧唧 吧唧
Squish! Squish, squish.
咯
Chog!
跑
Run!
咯
Chog.
她每天能学习十五个词
She gathers 15 words a day.
她的协调性也不太好
Her coordination is unstable at best.
在晚上会有些进步
In the evenings, there's progress.
她的头发每两天就能长一英寸
Her hair grows one inch every two days.
-我这里有相应的图表  -太好了
- I have a hair diagram here. - Excellent.
你可以走了 明天见
You may go. See you tomorrow.
先生 她是从哪里来的
Sir, where did she come from?
你的工作是收集数据
I believe your job is collecting data.
我想让你问我蠢问题时 我会告诉你的
When I add inane questions to it, I'll let you know.
他们从森林里回来后
"And so, when they returned from the wood...
她终于能和爸爸妈妈团聚了
"she was reunited with her Mummy and Daddy.
那天的晚餐 他们吃蛋糕直到吃吐为止
"That night, for dinner, they ate cake until they were sick.
重聚实在让他们太开心了
"They were so happy to be back together."
你素我爸爸吗 古德
You me Daddy, God?
普瑞姆说你不素
- I... - Prim say you not be.
贝拉来自无处
Bella nowhere girl.
那是什么地方 无处
Where that be? Nowhere?
你是个孤儿
You are an orphan.
你父母去世了
Your parents died.
然后你把父母切开么 古德
Then you cut parents up, God?
不
No.
他们是我的朋友
They were my friends.
是勇敢的探险者
They were brave explorers...
他们死于山崩 葬身在南美
and they were killed in a landslide in South America.
他们突破了知识的界限
They pushed the boundaries of what was known...
并付出了代价
and they paid the price.
但那是唯一的生存之道 贝拉
But that is the only way to live, Bella.
他们把你托付给我
They sent you to me to care for you.
死了
Dead?
是的 我亲爱的
I'm afraid so, my darling.
可怜的贝拉
Poor Bella.
但是爱古德
But love God.
睡在这里吧
Sleep here.
还是不了
No.
晚安 亲爱的贝拉
Good night, dear Bella.
这里 父母
This, parents.
秘鲁 对
Peru, yes.
为什么每个坚果你都要写在本子上
Why you pen book every nut?
我必须记录你的营养摄入
I must note down your nutritional intake.
有多少个
How many?
给贝拉讲讲别的地方
Tell Bella other places.
那是里斯本 葡萄牙首都
That's Lisbon, Portugal.
法国南部 阿尔卑斯山
The south of France. The Alps.
这是澳大利亚
Australia.
很远 很危险 那里的人和动物都很危险
Far away and dangerous, in both people and animal.
贝拉想看世界
Bella want look at world.
别
Just...
-贝拉  -嗯
Bella.
贝拉 我们不能上去的
Bella, I don't think we're allowed up here.
我们还是
Let's just...
贝拉
Bella.
不
No.
贝拉 很危险
Bella, this is dangerous.
贝拉
Bella.
不 贝拉
No, Bella.
古德
God.
外面 必须要去
Outside must go.
外面 不行 我们要工作
Outside? No, we work.
切手指
Cut fingers?
坎多斯带我去 坎多斯
Candles take me. Candles.
当然可以 如果
Of course I can. If...
不
No.
可以 我要出去
Yes. Out!
她有出去过吗
Has she ever been outside?
没有
No.
我为贝拉创造了一个有趣且安全的完美世界
I have created a perfectly entertaining and safe world for Bella.
我要出去
Now.
-贝拉  -现在
- Bella. - Now!
现在
Now!
贝拉
Bella.
外面有太多能杀掉你的东西 贝拉
You know, so many things outside can kill you, Bella.
杀死
Kill dead?
蛇 马车 尖嘴鸟 地震
Snakes, carriages, sharp-faced birds, earthquakes...
或是吸入毒草籽
inhalation of toxic grass seeds.
贝拉
Bella.
贝拉 你看
Bella. Look.
-杀了它  -什么
- Kill it. - What?
为什么你大拇指奇怪 古德
Why you funny thumbs, God?
在我很小的时候
Once when I was very small...
我父亲把我的拇指钉在一个小铁盒里
my father pinned my thumbs into a small iron case...
看看能否延缓骨骼的生长周期
to see whether he could retard the growth cycle of bones.
那时我太痛了
Now, the pain was so great...
为了阻止自己哭泣
to stop myself from weeping...
我紧盯着我其他的手指
I would stare deeply into my other fingers...
通过观察
and simply by observation...
开始分析流行病学的因素
begin to parse out the epidemiological elements.
他回来时
When he came back...
看到我在笑 很吃惊
to his surprise, I was smiling.
天哪
Good God.
他有很多不合常规的想法
He was a man of unconventional mind.
该走了
Time to go.
暴风雨就要来了
A storm approaches.
你为什么要这样吓唬她
Why must you scare her so?
她是个实验品
She's an experiment...
我必须控制外界条件
and I must control the conditions...
否则实验结果会不准确
or our results will not be pure.
停下 古德 我们走
Stop! God, we go!
不 贝拉
No, Bella.
贝拉想边走边吃冰淇淋
Bella want walk in ice cream.
不行
No.
贝拉想
Bella wants!
看到这张脸 别人会害怕我
My face. People scared of God.
嘲笑我
Laugh at God.
古德好看
God lovely.
像小狗的脸
Like dog face.
安静
Quite.
-停下 我要走  -不行
- Stop! Me walk. - No!
现在不行 还是永远不行
No now? No never?
就是不行
Just no.
-贝拉  -不
- Bella! - No!
-不 不 不  -喂 贝拉
- No! No! No! - Bella!
不
No!
-抱歉 抱歉  -不
- Sorry. Sorry. - No!
不 不
No! No!
很抱歉 亲爱的
I'm sorry, my darling.
天哪
Mother of God.
你对她做了什么
What did you do to her?
你为什么把她藏起来
Why are you hiding her?
告诉我这是什么意思 不然我就去报警了
Tell me what all this means, or I'll go to the police.
我会告诉你的 因为这是个美好的故事
I shall. For it is a happy tale.
这是一具很罕见的尸体 虽然死了 但离救活就差一步之遥
It is rare to get a body, albeit dead, but so close to life.
尸体还未出现僵硬
Rigor had not set in.
尚有余温
The body had hardly cooled.
没有脉搏
No pulse.
但体内还存在电流 这样我就能保住她的命
But some electric currents, so I could have kept her alive.
但你没有
But you didn't.
我对她所舍弃的人生一无所知
I knew nothing of the life she had abandoned...
我只知道她憎恶过去的生活 才选择抛弃一切
except she hated it so much that she had chosen not to be...
永远离世
and forever.
假若我们将她
What would she feel...
从其审慎选择的虚无来生中带离
on being dragged from her carefully chosen blank eternity...
接着关押在设备简陋且人手不足的疯人院 管教所 或者监狱
and forced to be put in one of our understaffed...
她会作何感想
poorly-equipped madhouses, reformatories or jails?
因为在这个基督教国家 人们视自杀为犯罪或是精神错乱的表现
For in this Christian nation, suicide is treated as lunacy or crime.
我又凭什么决定她的命运
Who was I to decide her fate?
但突然间 我意识到
But then there was also, on my part, a recognition.
我所有的研究就是为了等待这一时刻
All my research had come to this moment.
上天送来了一具死去的身躯
Fate had brought me a dead body...
它孕育的孩子却还活着
and a live infant.
显然是上天的安排
It was obvious.
是吗
It was?
把婴儿的脑子取出来
Take the infant's brain out...
移植进一个成年女性的头中 给她新生 然后观察她
and put it in the full-grown woman, reanimate her, and watch.
天啊
Jesus!
她知道吗
She knows?
不知道
No.
她是谁
Who was she?
不知道
No idea.
但你会宁愿希望贝拉不存在于这个世界上吗
But would you rather the world did not have Bella?
-普瑞姆女士  -嗯
Mrs. Prim?
贝拉找到了想要的快乐
Bella discover happy when she want.
你总是板着个脸 但我有招
You are a sour face, but I fix you.
闭上眼
Close eyes.
-不  -有点耐心 得花点时间
- No! - Just wait. It takes a moment.
她抓住了我带毛的那活
She grabbed my hairy business.
她有病
She's sick!
贝拉
Bella.
贝拉有新发现 必须分享
Bella have discover something I must share.
看着
Watch.
-如果我把黄瓜放进去呢  -不
- What if put cucumber in me? - No.
贝拉 贝拉
Bella! Bella!
不要再抚摸你自己了
Cease working yourself immediately.
什么
What?
在上流社会要举止斯文
In polite society, that is not done.
住手吧
Just do not.
那是什么
What... is that?
我父亲摘除了我的含氧腺和幽门腺
My father took out my oxyntic and pyloric glands...
所以我得自己造胃液
so I must make my own gastric juices.
老天 他为什么要这样做
Why in God's name would he do that?
为了探索未知
To discover what no one knew.
事实证明 理想情况下 我们需要胃液
Turns out we need them. Ideally.
贝拉
Bella...
你还没吃呢
you have not eaten.
不许丢
Do not.
晚安
Good night.
'Night.
我其实懂点浪漫 马克斯
You know, I'm actually something of a romantic, Max.
什么
What?
我在你和贝拉之间看到了爱的火花
I believe I see love between you and Bella.
呃 我 她
I... She is...
或许你应该娶她
Perhaps you should marry her.
什么
What?
我觉得她也爱你
I think she loves you.
作为旁观者 我见识过
I've seen people look at each other with love...
人们之间充满爱意的注视
as an observer.
当然 并非我亲身经历 是我亲眼所见
Not the subject, of course. I see it.
真的
You do?
我
I...
我确实对她有好感
I do have feelings for her.
所以 你愿意娶她吗
So, you would?
带贝拉走
Take Bella out.
贝拉
Bella...
我
I...
好玩吗
Feel funny?
舔 贝拉
Do Bella.
我还以为
I was wondering...
你养她是让她做情妇的
if perhaps you were raising her to be your mistress.
我知道这是一个阴暗的想法
A dark thought unworthy of me, I know.
所以 你没和她上床
So, you are not laying with her?
射精只会影响我的内环境稳定
Spermatic ejaculation can only induce homeostasis in me...
如果同时还对高级神经中枢进行长时间刺激
if accompanied by prolonged stimulation of higher nerve centers...
会使无导管腺体的压力产生变化 进而改变血液的化学成分
whose pressure on the ductless glands changes the chemistry of my blood...
这样的改变不止持续短短几分钟
not for a few spasmodic minutes...
更是会持续数天
but for many days.
什么
What?
我是个阉人 没办法操她
I am a eunuch and can't fuck her.
要让我的身体产生性反应
To get a sexual response from my body...
需要足以运作整个北伦敦的电量
would take the same amount of electricity as runs North London.
此外 我作为父亲的情感
Besides, my paternal feelings...
看来是超过了我对她的性欲
seem to outweigh my sexual thoughts.
我为我自己污浊的思想道歉
I apologize for my own dark thoughts.
一点也不污浊
Not dark at all.
事实上所有人的性欲从根本上来说都是不道德的
Men's, indeed all sexuality, is basically immoral.
并非所有都如此 先生
Not all, sir.
你到底想不想娶她
Do you wish to marry her or not?
我想和你结婚 做我的妻子吧
I wish to marry you. Be my wife.
让我们互相触摸对方的性器官吧
Let us touch each other's genital pieces.
呃 不
No. No.
我不想占你的便宜
I do not wish to take advantage of you.
你很特别
You are special.
等我们婚后再这样做吧
When we are wed.
有一个条件
One condition.
她必须也想要 我理解
She must desire it also, I understand.
那就是两个条件了
Two conditions, then.
除了你刚刚说的那个
That one you said...
你也必须一直跟我在这里生活
and you must live here with me, always.
我会起草一份法律协议
I will have a legal agreement drawn up.
这份协议很不寻常
Curious contract.
协议里有几处拼写错误
There are several spelling errors.
这并不会影响它的法律约束力 我向您保证
Immaterial to the legal bindingness of it, I assure you.
女方一定是个绝世佳人 条款才如此详尽
Must be quite a woman to warrant such binding.
不好意思 我需要借用一下卫生间
If you'll excuse me, I need to use the facilities.
你才五岁吗 这点都憋不住
Are you five years old that you can't hold your water?
我膀胱不好 先生 遗传自我父亲和我爷爷
Weak bladder, sir. Like my father before me and his before him.
你可能患了前列腺癌 去检查一下吧
You may have prostate cancer. Look into it.
行
Will do.
依协议来看 相信您就是贝拉·巴克斯特女士了
Ms. Bella Baxter, as per your contract, no doubt.
下午好 来访的男人
Good afternoon, visiting man.
想要我的帽子吗
Want my hat?
它适合我吗
Would it suit me?
适合
Yes.
又傻又可爱
It is foolish good.
我必须要见一见到底是怎样一位女士
I had to meet this woman...
为她起草的婚姻协议居然要把她关在家里
who would inspire such a contract of marriage that imprisons her.
你是什么意思
What you mean?
你要住在这里
You shall live here...
要与马克斯·麦克坎多斯先生和巴克斯特先生一同外出
travel with Mr. Max McCandles and Baxter abroad...
但不能进城区
but not go forth in the city.
我知道
I see.
他们很爱我
They love me tight.
我理解
I understand why.
我得掐你一下 来确定你到底是不是真的
I have to pinch you, to see if you are real.
你才不能 啊
You will not...
你素谁
Who is you?
我是邓肯·维德伯恩先生
Mr. Duncan Wedderburn.
开门
Open.
你怎么上来的
How you get up here?
我爬上来的
I climbed.
你看我很久了吗
You were watch me long?
没多久
Not long.
你不会看到我为了寻开心而抚摸自己了吧
You did not see me working on myself to get happiness, did you?
我知道这样的举止不斯文
It is not polites, I know.
我不在乎上流社会的规矩
Do not care for polite society.
那太无聊了
It's fucking boring.
能摧毁一个人的灵魂
Destroys one's soul.
古德不相信灵魂
God not believe in soul.
我认为古德正是灵魂这个概念的创始人
I think God's the actual author of the soul idea.
古德温·巴克斯特
Godwin Baxter?
那只油尽灯枯的老狗
That burnt dog.
到底是怎么回事
What is that story?
你是个囚徒 而我要解放你
You are a prisoner and I aim to free you.
你身体里有一股渴望的力量
Something in you, some hungry being...
渴望体验 自由 和触碰
hungry for experience, freedom, touch.
发现未知并了解未知
To see the unknown and know it.
所以 你会问我为什么在这里
So, why am I here, you ask?
我周五要去里斯本 希望你能来
I'm going to Lisbon on Friday. I'd like you to come.
葡萄牙的里斯本
Lisbon of Portugal?
正是我说的里斯本
That is the Lisbon I speak of.
古德不会同意的
God never allow it.
所以我不问他
That's why I'm not asking him.
我问的是你
I'm asking you.
我觉得 贝拉和你待在一起不安全
Bella not safe with you, I think.
你当然不安全
You are absolutely... not.
能占用你一点宝贵的时间吗 亲爱的古德
May I have a moment of value time, dear God?
当然 贝拉
Of course, Bella.
我想告诉你一个大消息
I wanted to tell you big news.
贝拉兴奋得头晕目眩
Bella is dizzy with excite.
是什么事
What is it?
今天午夜
Tonight, at midnight...
我悄悄和一个叫邓肯·维德伯恩的男人逃走
I secretly run away with one Duncan Wedderburn.
什么
What?
你会想要阻止我
You will wish to stop me.
我会阻止你
I shall stop you.
你把贝拉管得太严了
You hold Bella too tight.
我必须去海上看看
I must set forth into waters.
我们可以旅行
We can travel.
我 你 和马克斯
You, me, and Max whom, I will remind you...
我得提醒你 你和马克斯订婚了
you are betrothed to.
我会和马克斯结婚
I will marry Max...
因为他看起来很合适做我丈夫
as he seems right for that...
但首先 我要和邓肯·维德伯恩去冒险
but first, I shall adventure on Duncan Wedderburn...
虽然他对我受伤毫不在意
who, I think, cares little of damage to me...
但他也很有趣
but will be interesting as well.
我不会让你去的
I can't let you go.
吻我 然后让我离开
Kiss me and set me forth.
否则
If you do not...
贝拉的内脏会因仇恨而腐烂
Bella's insides shall turn rotten with hate.
-仇恨  -仇恨
- Hate? - Hate.
打开包 普瑞姆
Unpack those bags, Prim.
古德温告诉我你的计划了
Godwin has told me your plan.
我不怪你 贝拉
I do not blame you, Bella.
那个人是个无赖和浪子
That man is a cad and a rake.
他用阴险的手段让天真的女人动心
He has insidious ways of getting under a naive woman's skin.
可能是他看我的眼神
It is mostly his eyes on mine.
触摸我双腿之间的手
And his hands when between Bella's legs...
和听不清的轻声细语
and whisper words I can't hear...
但让我欲火焚身
but heat in my body.
天啊 贝拉
Jesus, Bella.
我们订婚了
We are engaged.
我爱你
I love you.
我回来之后 我们就结婚
And when I return, we marriage...
像树枝上的两只鸽子一样快乐
and be happy as two doves on a branch.
-你觉得我需要旅行帽吗  -不
- You think I need travel hat? - No!
这件事不可能发生
This will not do.
我不许你去
It cannot!
我要亲自对付这个人
I'll see to this man myself.
我会把他英俊的脸打得血肉模糊
I will beat his handsome face into a porridge of blood and bones!
马克斯 你脸红了
Max, you are flushed...
我居然看到了不一样的马克思
and I am too at sight of different Max.
不好意思
I apologize...
但我不会让一个满是恶意 心里完全没有你的男人欺骗你
but I will not let a man that I know has nothing but ill intent in his mind... and nothing for you in his heart trick you.
我他妈要把他的头打烂
I will smash his fucking head in.
贝拉 这
Bella? It...
贝拉
Bella.
再见 未来的鸽子
Goodbye, later dove.
我会在大冒险之后回来见你
I will see you after grand adventure.
古德
God?
她走了
She's gone.
我早餐在喝波特酒
I am having port for breakfast.
它异常好喝
It is strangely delicious.
你为什么不阻止她
Why did you not stop her?
她本就有自由意志
She is a being of free will.
她现在在外面孤身一人
She's now out there. Alone.
她会没事的
She will be fine.
我是个傻瓜 我本该阻止她的
I'm a fool. I should have stopped her.
我们是搞科学的人
We are men of science.
你不该这么情绪化
This emotionality is unseemly.
我只希望她没事
I just hope she's all right.
你是我见过的最美的女人
You are the most beautiful woman I've ever seen.
我没说谎 我和很多女人在一起过
I will not lie, I have been with many.
普瑞姆女士说 你身上有一百个女人的香水味
Mrs. Prim said you were wolf with scent of hundred women on you.
她说少了
She undersells it.
好的 牡蛎
Okay. Oysters.
你吃过牡蛎吗
Have you had them before?
没有
I have not.
开壳 去壳 一口吞掉
Shuck, chuck and bubble.
真不错
Rollicking.
等等 贝拉
Wait. Bella.
里斯本
修道士和修女们会用蛋白来浆洗衣服
So, nuns and monks would starch their clothes with egg whites...
然后用蛋黄来做蛋挞
and, with the yolks, make these tarts.
这该怎么吃呢
Now, how to eat them?
我猜是用嘴吃
I will guess through the mouth.
它们不应该一小口一小口地吃
They must not be eaten dainty flake by dainty flake...
而应该大口享用 就像享受生活一样
but inhaled with gusto, like life itself.
棒极了
Incredible.
这是谁做的 我还想要几个
Who made these? We need more.
没了 一个够了 再多就过分了
No more. One's enough. Any more is too much.
现在是午休时间
It's siesta time.
什么是午休时间
What is siesta?
人们为什么不能
Why do people not just do this...
一直做爱呢
all the time?
好吧 不是我自夸
Well, at the risk of being immodest...
你刚刚和最棒的人做了三次
you've just been thrice fucked by the very best.
可能没有其他男人能带给你这样的快乐
It's probable no other man would ever bring you to the raptures I have.
真为你感到难过
I feel bad for you.
那我就只和你一起做激烈跳跃
Well, then it will just be you I do furious jumping with.
激烈跳跃
Furious jumping?
我喜欢这个说法
I love that.
我休息好了
I'm rested.
我们再来一次
Let us go again.
再一次
Again?
遗憾的是
Unfortunately...
即使是我也有极限
even I have my limits.
男人不能索要无度
Men cannot keep coming back for more.
这是生理问题吗
It is a physiological problem?
是男人的弱点吗
A weakness in men?
嗯
Well...
可能吧
Perhaps so.
如果还不算太晚的话
You'd be advised, if it's not too late...
你最好别爱上我
not to fall in love with me.
我不能承诺任何的
I have very little to offer...
天长地久
in the way of constancy.
只有冒险
Just adventure.
知道了
I see.
睡觉吧
Let us sleep.
女士需要打车吗
Taxi, madam?
晚上好
Good evening...
邓肯·维德伯恩
Duncan Wedderburn.
贝拉 你去哪儿了 你怎么不见了
Bella, where were you? You disappeared.
我没有
I did not.
没有人会消失
Nobody can just disappear.
什么
What?
人们能消失吗
Can they? Disappear?
不能 当然不能 你在说什么鬼话
No, of course not. What the fuck are you talking...
你去哪儿了
Where were you?
我想吃蛋挞 然后经历了一场冒险
I wanted a tart and then an adventure befell me.
我不知道怎么回来 然后就听到了一个声音
I did not know how to return and then I heard it.
电车的声音
The tram.
我朝着声音走过去 还真让我找到了
I will walk to the noise, and I found it.
我很惊喜
Amazement to Bella.
我真是天生的探险家
Explorer bloods in me.
贝拉 你独自外出是很危险的
Bella, it's dangerous to go out without me.
我刚经历了一次冒险 只找到了糖和暴力
I have adventured it and found nothing but sugar and violence.
这是最迷人的
It is most charming.
我没事
I am fine.
现在 我必须躺下 你必须压在我身上做更多激烈跳跃
Now, I must lie down and you must lie down on top of me and do more furious jumping.
凯蒂
Kitty.
你看过王尔德在伦敦的新剧吗
Did you see the new show in London by Wilde?
妙趣横生
Marvelously witty.
我很喜欢
I loved it.
一个手提包
"A handbag."
贝拉
Bella.
怎么了
What?
如果这令人作呕 我不吐出来还能干嘛
Why I keep it in my mouth if it is revolting?
我之前对杰拉德这么说过
I have said that before to Gerald.
-如果你明白我的意思  -呃
If you catch my drift.
你真邪恶
You are wicked.
噢 因为你指的是他的鸡鸡
Oh. Because you mean his penis.
邓肯的鸡鸡有时候有点咸
Duncan's can sometimes be salty.
老天啊 贝拉
Good God, Bella.
我必须去打那个小孩一顿
I must go punch that baby.
贝拉
Bella.
你的行为太荒谬了
Your behavior is unconscionable.
你能听话吗
Will you behave?
食物让我喉咙发干
The food was cacking my throat...
那个孩子哭得让我气恼
the baby annoying...
还有那个女人的话让我厌烦
and the woman boring with words.
你将会回到餐桌前
You will rejoin the table...
只说以下三句话
and will confine yourself to the following three phrases...
太神奇了 高兴极了
"How marvelous!", "Delighted"...
还有 他们怎么把糕点做得这么酥脆的 明白吗
and "How did they make the pastry so crisp?" Yes?
你弄疼贝拉了
You are hurting Bella.
抱歉
Sorry.
是我不够理智
Reason does not penetrate.
我们走
Let us go.
你喜欢里斯本吗 贝拉
Are you enjoying Lisbon, Bella?
高兴极了
Delighted.
凯蒂 你亲爱的父亲还好吗
Kitty, how is your dear father?
他很不好
He's very unwell.
我担心他活不过今年
I fear he will not see the year out.
-噢  -太神奇了
How marvelous.
他们怎么把糕点做得这么酥脆的
How did they get the pastry so crisp?
老天啊
Good God.
怎么了
What is it?
她寄来的
From her.
我好 里斯本
"Me good. Lisbon.
糖挞每天都舔我
"Sugar tart lick me all day."
至少都是一整句话
At least I hope that's all one sentence, anyway.
-你觉得他们  -在做爱
- Do you think they're... - Fucking?
对
Yes.
还有
Also...
她在给有轨电车口交
fellating a tram.
你也头疼吗 邓肯·维德伯恩
Does your head ache too, Duncan Wedderburn?
我也饿得想吃晚饭了
And I also am starving for dinner.
你他妈去哪了
Where the fuck were you?
你是维多利亚·帕辛顿
Victoria Blessington?
我有很多年没见过你了
I haven't seen you for years.
你还是没见到她
And you still have not...
因为我是贝拉·巴克斯特
as I am Bella Baxter...
奇怪的羽毛女士
strange feathered lady.
真抱歉 我发誓你跟她长得一模一样
I apologize. I could've sworn you were she.
没错
Right.
我们能走了吗
Shall we?
牛排 鱼
The steak, the fish...
罐装小焦糖
little caramel things in pots...
跟那桌的一样
that old spotted people over there have.
我不想吃罐装小焦糖
I don't want caramel in pots.
当然不是给你的 都是给贝拉的
Of course not. That was all for Bella.
你点你要的吧
Order at your whim.
贝拉外出探险 你很生气
You are cross at Bella's outings and adventures.
但邓肯·维德伯恩在与贝拉·巴克斯特
And yet we must discover by whim...
第一天在里斯本爱恋时对她说
as spoken by Duncan Wedderburn to Bella Baxter...
我们必须通过突发奇想来探索
day one of Lisbon love affair.
说得好
Touché.
请理解我 我从未在古德的房子外生活过
Understand me never lived outside God's house.
什么
What?
所以 贝拉有太多东西需要探索
So, Bella so much to discover...
而你悲伤的表情
and your sad face...
让我发现 我对你很愤怒
makes me discover angry feelings for you.
行
Right.
我成了我最恨痛的那种人
I have become the very thing I hate...
渴求爱的妖物
a grasping succubus of a lover.
我赶走了许多爱上我的人 现在自己却要被赶走了
I've pried many of them off me and now I'm it.
操
Fuck!
你和我一样 现在是自由的生物
You, like me, are a creature of freedom in the moments.
你为什么一直眨眼
What do you keep doing that for?
那个男的一直朝我眨眼
A man over there repeated blinks at me.
我也眨眼
I blink back.
出于礼貌 应该是
For polites, I think.
我们要去镇上跳舞了 请和我们一起吧
We are going to dance in town. Please join us.
我从没在镇上跳过舞
I have never danced in town.
邓肯 不行
- Duncan! - Can't!
你非常生气
You're quite mad.
不要说话了 你的声音让贝拉愤怒
Stop talking as your sounds make Bella angry!
我要说
I will not stop talking.
如果我有想说的话 我就要
If I have something to say I'll...
啊
Ouch.
行吧
All right.
这是什么
What's this?
之前 有一个人教我下国际象棋
A man was teaching me chess...
他说他认为我的皮肤是他摸过最柔软的
and he said he thought I would probably have the softest skin he had ever touched.
我说 如果是的话 可以在大腿内侧测试
And I said, if I did it would be the inner thighs to test...
因为那里的表皮最光滑
as that is where the epidermis is at its most fine.
所以我们就测试了
So we tested...
确实是最柔软的
and it was the softest ever.
我想知道软度会不会有区别
I wondered if perhaps they're not equal in softitude.
确实也不同
Indeed they were not.
所以我就记录了一下哪个是哪个
So I made sure to note it, remembering which was which.
刚刚你说的要舔我呢
What of the tongue play you were about to perform?
你不舔了吗
Is that not happening?
你
You...
你心事重重
You are troubled.
他和你上床了吗
Did he lie with you?
没有 我们靠着墙
No, we were against a wall.
你在他身上了激烈跳跃了吗
Did you furious jump him?
没有 他只是快速舔了我的阴蒂
No, he just fast-licked my clitoris.
我内心的欲火需要释放 所以我就释放出来了
I had the heat that needed release, so at my request it was.
你也可以舔我
You, too, may tongue play me...
所以我不明白这种复杂的情绪
so I'm not understanding this complicated feeling.
你在哭吗
Are you now crying?
你真是个迷惑的人 邓肯·维德伯恩
What a confusing person you are, Duncan Wedderburn.
肝脏
A liver.
一个小切口
A small incision...
就足够了
is all that is needed.
我一早上都在用氯仿麻醉山羊
I was chloroforming goats all morning.
可能我也吸入太多了
I may have ingested too much.
我大胆地猜测 您因为贝拉不在而感到不安
I am going to venture to suggest you are upset by Bella's absence.
您狂喝波特酒
The liters of port...
我晚上还听到您在哭
the sobbing I hear at night.
我的老天 你个碎嘴的蠢货
Good God, man! You prattle like an imbecile.
她已经走了
She is gone!
我是个科学家
I am a man of science.
我只需要考虑推进我的项目
I just need to engage in, and continue, the project.
仅此而已 我要继续下一个研究项目了
That is all. I must go on to the next thing.
我们的感情必须搁置一旁
Our feelings must be put aside.
你觉得如果我的父亲不把科学与进步放在第一位
Do you think my father could have branded me...
他还会像他那样
with hot irons on the genitals the way he did...
用烙铁给我的生殖器打烙印吗
if he could not put science and progress first?
打烙印
Branded you?
我们找一具尸体吧
Let us find a body.
找什么
A what?
嗨 早上好
Hello. Good morning.
早上好 亲爱的
Good morning, darling.
之前我没有全心全意支持你的冒险精神
I haven't been very supportive of your adventurous spirit.
所以我准备了一个惊喜
So I have a surprise for you.
进来吧
Get in.
-我们换酒店了吗  -看窗外 贝拉
- We changed hotels? - Look out the window, Bella.
-我们在船上  -是的
- We're on boat? - Indeed.
你想把贝拉困在海上 我决定要带你踏上新的冒险
- You aim to trap Bella at sea. - I aim to give you a new adventure.
我想我能更容易找到你
I suppose it's true you'll be easier to find.
来吧 扒光我的衣服
Come, disrobe me.
骑上来
Ride me.
等会儿我们可以去前甲板上喝鸡尾酒
And we'll then have cocktails on foredeck.
贝拉
Bella.
Bella!
蓝色 蓝色 蓝色
Blue. Blue. Blue.
敢在我身上拉屎
Shit on me?
畜生
Fucker!
女士
Madam.
我们什么时候靠岸
When do we stop?
雅典 还有三天
Athens. Three days.
轮船
瞧瞧 那个女人着火了
That woman's on fire, look.
我知道你在生我的气
I know you're upset with me.
原谅我诱拐了你 但这都是出于爱
Forgive my kidnapping of you, but it was for love.
这就是个浪漫的玩笑 别像个婊子似的
A romantic jape. Don't be such a cunt about it.
-我口渴了  -当然了 亲爱的
- I want a drink. - Of course, my darling.
这艘船很有意思 还有许多未知等着你去探索
The ship is fun, a whole world to explore.
你爱我吗 我爱你
Do you love me? I love you.
告诉我 我应该自我探寻些什么 才能确定到底爱不爱你
Describe the elements I should be looking for within myself to be sure.
你能感觉到你是爱我还是不爱我
You just feel it or not.
就像古德所说 爱毫无依据
So it is no evidence base, as God would say.
-那要如何仅凭经验判断呢  -你他妈在说什么鬼话
- So how judge it empirically? - What the fuck are you talking about?
你是谁
Who are you?
你不知道香蕉是什么 你也没听说过国际象棋
You don't know what bananas are, you've never heard of chess...
你却知道什么叫凭经验判断
and yet you know what "empirically" means.
贝拉口渴了 我说了两遍了
Bella wants a drink. I said twice now.
我从来没有过这样的感觉
I've never felt anything like this.
对你来说也是这样吗
Is this true for you?
我想 凭经验来说 是这样的
I suppose, empirically it is.
古德温
笔没墨了
I'm out of ink.
那我去给你拿墨水 亲爱的
Then ink you shall have, my love.
你好啊 有趣的老太太
Hello, interesting older lady.
我得摸摸你的头发
I must touch your hair.
我也注意到了你的头发
I also noticed your hair.
像丝绸披在晶莹透亮 闪闪发光的鸡蛋上一样
Just like silk on a translucent, glowing egg.
这样花哨的辞藻让我莫名有些兴奋
That is fancy words that excite me somehow.
我看见你和那边的帅哥在一起
I saw you're with handsome over there.
洁白的牙齿和梆硬的老二
White teeth and a hard cock.
邓肯·维德伯恩
Duncan Wedderburn.
他的牙齿很硬 他的鸡鸡也很白
His teeth are also hard. His penis is also white.
-希望他有好活  -他是我的唯一
- Good lay, I hope. - He is my only.
但我发现他会引起我全身产生异样的感觉
But I find him to elicit exceptional sensations throughout my whole body...
这让我愉悦地尖叫
that leave me yelping happily.
我也希望把他的身体 或者说尸体 抛进海里
I also wish to dash his body, form, cadaver, into the sea.
这个男人也会在你身上跳来跳去吗
Is this man jumping on your body?
不 他不会
No, he is not.
我已经20年没和人上过床了
I haven't been bedded in 20 years.
什么
What?
太糟糕了
That is terrible.
这并没有什么好担忧的
It doesn't concern me greatly.
几十年过去了
As years have passed...
真正让我担忧的是我的脑子
what's in between my ears is my big concern.
而不是
What's in between my legs...
我两腿之间的乐趣
much less so.
绝望的合理化 玛莎
A desperate rationalization, Martha.
噢 这是哈利·阿斯特利
Oh, this is Harry Astley.
别把他说的话放在心上
Don't take what he says too much to heart.
他是个愤世嫉俗的人
He's a cynic.
女士
Madam.
我是贝拉·巴克斯特
I am Bella Baxter.
我不懂什么叫愤世嫉俗
I do not know what this "cynic" is.
贝拉
Bella.
墨水
Ink.
邓肯·维德伯恩 我结识了新的朋友 同僚 伙伴
Duncan Wedderburn, I have made friends, colleagues, comrades.
哈利·阿斯特利
Harry Astley.
这是玛莎
This is Martha.
她是我的新朋友 她都20年没被操过了
She is my new friend who has not been fucked in 20 years.
这难道不令人惊讶吗
Is that not astonishment?
我希望你有用手来取悦自己
I hope you use your hand between your legs to keep yourself happy.
天哪 贝拉 你不能说这种话
Good God, Bella, you cannot speak like this.
上流社会要举止文雅 我给忘了
Polites of society. I forgot.
上流社会
Polite society...
会毁了你
will destroy you.
-是吗  -是啊 有一定的道理
- It will? - Yeah, there's some truth to that.
看来我们都同意这一点
We all agreed on that.
至于你问的关于我自己动手的问题
As to your enquiry on my hand.
是的 我有时候会这么做
Occasionally, yes.
这可让我安心多了
That is much reassuring news.
-我们应该一起用餐  -好吧 其实
- We shall all dine together. - Well, actually...
我们在一条船上 都没法逃走
We are all on a ship and cannot escape...
那就让我们在这儿纵情享乐 横渡海洋环球航行吧
and there is a world to enjoy, traverse, circumnavigate.
难道她不能交朋友吗 维德伯恩先生
Or can she not have friends, Mr. Wedderburn?
好极了
Delighted.
嫁给我
Marry me.
什么
What?
我本想把你扔在一边
I meant to throw you aside.
几个月后再把你打发走 但现在我做不到了
A few months and send you packing, but I cannot.
你快说你会嫁给我 从来没人能俘获我的心 除了你
Say you'll marry me. No one's ever captured my heart. You have.
这有点难办
It is tricky...
因为我已经和马克斯·麦克坎多斯先生订婚了
as I am engaged to Mr. Max McCandles.
什么
What?
有人已对我许下执子之手的诺言
My hand has taken by another.
这个说法我以前听过 但并不明白
It is a saying I heard, but did not understand.
结婚不是只是牵手 而是拥有彼此的一切不是吗？
You do not take just the hand, but all, do you not?
是你逃离了他 和我一起来
You ran away with me from him.
每次回顾以前的事 我总是很难搞清重点
A recounting of events, the point of which is elusive to me.
你选择了我 而不是他
You chose me over him.
只是暂时的
For now.
只是因为好玩
For fun.
我他妈要把你从船上扔下去
I'll fucking throw you overboard!
那么 你到底是想娶我还是杀我
So you wish to marry me or kill me?
-这是求婚吗  -不是
- Is that the proposal? - No.
去赌场
Going to the casino.
呃 没关系
That's fine.
她还在成长
She is coming along.
再试一次吧
Let's try again.
大肌肉群动作技能会发展得较为缓慢
Gross motor skills will develop slowly...
但你会进步很快的
but you will progress fast.
费利西蒂
Felicity.
看来没那么快
Not that fast.
我在读爱默生的书
I am reading Emerson.
他谈到了男人如何改善自我
He speaks about the improvement of men.
我不知道他为什么不给女人提建议
I do not know why he does not give advice to women.
或许他根本就不懂女人
Perhaps he does not know any.
试试读一读歌德
Try and read Goethe.
读哲学就是在浪费时间 贝拉
Philosophy is a waste of time, Bella.
真的吗 你再讲讲
Really? Say more.
不 哈利 你个笨蛋
No, no, Harry, you wretch.
哲学是必不可缺之物
It is integral.
人和社会都可以由此得到改善
People and society can be improved.
改善 发展 进步 成长 是全人类共同的目标
It is the goal of all to improve, advance, progress, grow.
我对这一点深有其感 而且我相信我的观点可以代表所有人
I know this in me, and I am sure I am indicative of all.
相信我 你绝对是独一无二的 贝拉 各方面都是
Trust me, you are definitely unique, Bella, in all ways.
但这种通过哲学进行的改良
But this improvement through philosophy...
其实是人们试图逃避自己就是残暴的野兽这一事实
is people trying to run away from the fact that we are all cruel beasts.
生来如此 死亦如此
Born that way, die that way.
这是一种消极观点 哈利
It is a dark view of things, Harry.
贝拉
Bella...
去我们的船舱里
let us take the air...
透透气吧
in our cabin.
但这两个人还在争论不休
But these two are fighting...
各种想法在贝拉的脑海和心里乱撞
and ideas are banging around in Bella's head and heart...
就像暴风雨中摇晃的灯光
like lights in a storm.
你现在老是在看书啊 贝拉
You're always reading now, Bella.
你说话的方式不像以前那样可爱了
You're losing some of your adorable way of speaking.
和所有人一样
I am a changingable feast...
我是一场变幻莫测的盛宴
as are all of we.
爱默生是这么说的 但哈利却不同意这话
Apparently according to Emerson, disagreed with by Harry.
来啊 来啊 走吧
Come, come. Just come.
你挡住光了
You are in my sun.
啥
What?
跟我来
Come.
我正忙着买醉呢
Busy drinking heavily.
忙着狂输呢
Busy losing heavily.
我得去见玛莎
I must go meet Martha.
玛莎
Martha.
问题就是她
She is the problem.
我要把那个喷了香水的肉块扔海里
I'll throw that perfumed bag of flesh overboard.
你敢扔试试
I dare you.
玛莎
Martha!
她在哪里
Where is she?
你在哪里
Where are you, fuck.
她在哪里
Where is she?
-你要去哪  -我要把她丢进海里
- Where are you going? - She's going over the side.
哦 太神奇了
Oh, marvelous!
我从没想过会被谋杀
I never imagined being murdered.
太戏剧化了
How dramatic.
她看起来乐意去死 很抱歉挡了你的路
Well, she seems happy to die. I'm sorry for getting in your way.
有意思
Exciting.
我在酒吧等你
I'll be in the bar.
你让我思考 犹豫
You have made me think, cogitate...
在错误 愚蠢 惹人烦的
perambulate on ideas that are wrong...
思想中徘徊
erroneous and nonsensically annoying...
我失眠了
that lead me not to sleep.
然后呢
So...
你说人都是残忍的
You say all are cruel.
我否定 拒绝
And I disagree, disavow...
表示不是这样的
and say no not.
但是在邓肯面前
But when with Duncan...
我心中的残忍开始冒泡
the cruel just bubbles up in me.
说明你有自己的判断力
That shows good judgment.
他是个十足的蠢货
He is a pretty moron.
不
No.
我不想残忍
I do not wish to be cruel.
我必须改进自己这一面
I must improve this aspect of myself.
你不了解全世界
You don't know the world.
你有恐惧
And you fear it.
我不恐惧
I do not fear it.
你想看看这个世界真实的样子吗
Do you want to see what the world is really like?
我带你看
I'll show you.
好
Yes.
Of course.
亚历山大
你听见了吗
Do you hear that?
那是什么
What is it?
-很多死婴  -噢
Lot of dead babies.
那里一定很热吧
Must be hot.
我们得去帮帮他们
We must go help them.
怎么帮
How will we do that?
我们一下去
We go down there...
他们会理所当然的把我们绑上抢 劫强 奸我们
they'll quite rightfully rope us, rob us, and rape us.
如果换个位置 他们在这里 我们在下面
And if they were here and we were there...
我们也会这么做
we'd do the same to them.
贝拉
Bella.
船要开走了 女士
We are casting off, ma'am.
我得回去
But I have to go back.
我得把钱分给旅馆附近的穷人
I must give this money to the poor near the hotel...
也就是他们说的贫民窟里的人
in what they call a slum.
我们会留在岸上 女士
We're staying ashore, ma'am.
我们可以帮您办这件事
We could take care of that for you.
你们可以吗
You can?
当然
Of course.
您很大方
It is generous of you.
他们需要钱
They need money.
谁都需要钱
Everyone does.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你 把船长叫过来 一定要找到那个该死的小偷
You! Get me the captain. Now we'll find this fucking thief.
贝拉
Bella!
我们被抢劫了
We've been robbed!
我赢了
I won.
我赢得了所有东西
I won everything...
以前从来没有过
like never before.
现在 都没了
And now it's gone.
没人抢你东西
You've not been robbed.
-我拿走了  -为什么
- I took it. - For what?
我拿走了
I took it.
我太累了
I'm so tired.
或者也许只是我的炅魂如此
Or maybe just my spirit is.
我的灵魂被钳制 蹂躏
My soul has been buckled, crumpled...
打压 邓肯·维德伯恩
flattened, Duncan Wedderburn...
被我看到的东西折磨
by the sights I have seen.
所以 不需要找船长了 是吧先生
So, no need for the captain then, sir?
滚开 别让我把你们打得满地找牙
Fuck off before I break all your teeth.
好的 先生
Indeed, sir.
放哪里了
Where is it?
你是安全起见藏起来了
You hid it for safety.
我喝醉了 还愚蠢地扔得到处都是 这就让人放心了
I was drunk and foolishly left it everywhere. What a relief.
我没有藏起来
I did not hide it.
我把它给外面的穷人了
I gave it to those poor people out there.
金钱本身就是一种疾病
Money is its own form of sickness...
也代表了一种贫瘠
and all the scarcity of it.
我又凭什么
And who am I...
躺在羽毛床中
lying in a feather bed...
同时 却有婴儿们
while dead babies...
在沟渠中死去
lie in a ditch?
邓肯
Duncan.
你干了什么
You what?
我想要一个安慰的拥抱
I am expecting a hug of solace.
你
You...
我需要给这个世界奉献一些东西
I need to offer something to the world.
但目前我什么都没有
And yet I have nothing.
除了一些钱
Except some money.
贝拉·巴克斯特今天过得很不好
It is a bad day for Bella Baxter.
我的钱他妈在哪
Where is my fucking money?
我刚才告诉你了
I just told you.
我把它给穷人了
I gave it away to the poor.
我不是刚才告诉你滚出去了吗
I thought I told you to fuck off!
乘务通知我
The steward informs me...
说您的资金可能不足 无法清偿您的账户 先生
that you may not have sufficient funds to make good your account, sir.
-这个 我  -这估计是真的
- Well, I... - That is probably true.
我把你的钱交给几位好人
I gave it all to some nice men...
他们把钱给
to pass on...
那些贫民窟穷人
to the slum poor.
你们会在下一个港口下船
You'll be put ashore at the next port...
到那之前都只能拥有船员配给 先生
and confined to crew's rations until then, sir.
-晚安  -你怎么敢
- Good evening. - How dare you?
死去的 盲人婴儿
"Dead, blind babies...
咬了哈利
"bit Harry.
我的嘴
"My mouth...
满是鲜血
"was full of blood."
可怜的贝拉
Poor Bella.
狼狈不堪
She is a ruin.
-你的手怎么样了  -没事了
- How's your hand? - It's fine.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你只是在帮助我理解
You were trying to help me understand.
不我 其实想要伤害你
No. I actually wanted to hurt you.
不能忍受看到一个人拥有傻傻但美好的快乐
Couldn't bear to see such dumb, beautiful happiness in someone.
我很残忍
It was cruel of me.
我不抱歉
I am not sorry.
如果我了解这个世界 我可以让它变得更好
If I know the world, I can improve it.
你不能
You can't.
这才是真正的关键点
That is the real point.
不要相信宗教的谎言
Don't accept the lie of religion...
社会主义
socialism...
资本主义
capitalism.
人类已经完蛋了
We are a fucked species.
你得知道 希望是会破碎的
Know it. Hope is smashable.
但现实主义不会
Realism is not.
用真相保护自己
Protect yourself with the truth.
我知道你现在是什么了 哈利
I realize what you are now, Harry.
一个受伤的小男孩不能承受世界带来的伤痛
Just a broken little boy who cannot bear the pain of the world.
我也觉得
I suppose so.
再见了 哈利
Goodbye, Harry.
我们得在马赛下船了
We get thrown off in Marseille.
那你为什么还跟他在一起
Why do you stay with him?
我一直觉得这样会更好
I always think it will be better.
当然了
'Course you do.
巴黎
我听说过巴黎的美景
I have heard great things of the beauty of Paris.
我会他妈的把你的狗踢死
I'll fucking kick your dog to death.
他妈的
Fucking...
我们在巴黎身无分文
Paris with no money.
-你有什么好建议 贝拉  -我会找到旅馆的
- What do you suggest we do, Bella? - I will get us a hotel.
别担心
Do not worry.
啊哈 用什么找 我们可没钱
With what? We have no money.
这难道不是一场有趣的实验吗
Is it not an interesting experiment?
我们一无所有
We have nothing.
-我们现在应该怎么生存  -我不知道
- How will we live now? - I don't know!
没错 这就是一场实验
Exactly, that is the experiment.
我们现在就是穷人
We are now the poor.
而且 很多探险家也遇见过这些困难
Also, many adventurers have faced these odds.
比如 鲁滨逊·克鲁索
Robinson Crusoe, for example.
自私自利没心没肺 粗心大意的贱人
Selfish, thoughtless, careless bitch.
我不是没心没肺 邓肯
I'm not thoughtless, Duncan.
虽然我的
And while it is true my ability...
逻辑思维能力
to think things through to the logical conclusions is not...
确实不强
strong...
我的确帮助了那些受苦受难的人
I did help those suffering people.
我害了我们
I have ruined us...
如你所说
as you pointed out...
但我相信我的初心是好的
but I do believe my actions come from a good place.
快他妈闭嘴吧
Shut the fuck up.
我会让我们住进旅馆的
I will get us a hotel.
下午好 夫人
Good afternoon, madam.
你好 这位美丽可人的英伦玫瑰
Good day, my fresh, darling English Rose.
这是一家旅馆吗
Is this a hotel?
我们还有房间
We have rooms.
你是想找份工作吗
Are you looking for work?
一间房间多少钱
How much is a room?
我就收你十法郎一小时好了
I'll charge you 10 francs an hour.
你收他们三十
You charge them 30.
大家都开心
Everyone's happy.
我知道了
I see.
沙佩勒先生
Monsieur Chapelle.
这位是新来的伦敦人
Fresh from London.
你好
Hello.
好了 你进去吧
So, off you go.
现在 我有点困惑
At this point, I am confused.
你不是来这工作的吗
You're not here to work?
你就去吧
Come on.
跟他上床 让他进入你的身体
Lie with him, let him cock you a bit...
赚点小钱
and make some nice francs.
我知道了
I see.
他会给我钱吗
He would pay me for this?
会
Yes.
如果你缺钱
If you need money...
这就是最短的捷径
it is the shortest route to it.
还没有别的男人进入过我的身体
I have never been cocked by another man...
但是现在有点想了
and yet have wondered on that.
而且我缺钱
And am in need of funds.
我认为 这是多种情况交织在一起导致的结果
It is, I believe, a confluence of circumstances...
有点像是命运使然
I regard as almost fate-like.
那就开干吧
Let us do this.
十六号房间
Room 16.
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
真神秘
Mysterious.
我们需要前戏一下吗
Should we warm me up a bit...
你好 先生
Good day, sir.
吃巧克力闪电泡芙吗
Éclair au chocolat?
我得到了钱 还得到了一些启发
I've come into some money and some enlightenment.
你偷来的吗
You stole it?
你总是说 你床上功夫世界第一
You've always said you're the best bedman in the world...
我也从不知道其他人怎么样 所以我也不知道这是不是真的
and I have never known another, so I knew not whether this was true.
但是现在我知道了
But now I do.
他简直糟糕透顶
And he was terrible...
他冲进我身体的时候 还发出了可怕的声音
and made ungodly noises as he thrust himself into me.
他仅仅猛冲了三次 邓肯·维德伯恩 三次已经是他的极限了
And a mere three thrusts, Duncan Wedderburn, was all he could manage.
我没忍住 笑了一声
I stifled a laugh...
当然 是出于礼貌
out of polites, of course.
接受了他给的钱 对他表示了感谢
I took his money. I thanked him.
我一路笑着去买了这些闪电泡芙
I laughed all the way to buy us these eclairs...
也一路深情地回忆
and I thought so fondly...
我们两个度过的一个个大汗淋漓的激烈夜晚
remembering the fierce sweaty nights of ours.
你为了钱和别人上床
You fucked for money?
这是一种实验
And as an experiment.
而且对我们的关系也有好处 让我对你更加倾心
And it is good for our relationship as it gladdens my heart toward you.
你最近总是哭哭啼啼 骂骂咧咧 我对你感情略有暗淡
My heart has been a bit dim on your weepy, sweary person lately.
你是个怪物 一个妓女 一个怪物
You are a monster. A whore and a monster.
你是来自地狱的恶魔
A demon sent from hell...
把我的灵魂撕裂
to rip my spirit to shreds.
你竟敢用海啸般的毁灭
To punish my tiny sins...
来惩罚我如此微小的罪孽
with a tsunami of destruction.
把我的心撕来扯去
To take my heart and pull it like taffy...
毁灭我
to ruin me.
我在你的脸上只能看到丑陋
I look at you, and I see nothing but ugliness.
最后那句话完全没有必要 也没有意义
That last bit was uncalled for and makes no sense...
因为你对我美貌的赞美实在是无趣
as your odes to my beauty have been boring...
但却从未停止
but constant.
仅仅是因为
And the simple act...
一个陌生男子与我同床
of letting a strange man ride on me...
你就抹去了所有的赞美
has erased all that?
妈的
Fuck!
你成了妓女
You whored yourself.
你现在又要给我解释这件事的弊端了
Which you are now going to explain to me is bad.
我做什么都不能让你满意吗
Can I never win with you?
这是一个女人最底线的行为了
It is the worst thing women can do.
我们肯定不能结婚了
We should definitely never marry.
我是个满是缺陷 却乐于尝试的人
I am a flawed, experimenting person...
我需要一个更能谅解我的丈夫
and I will need a husband with a more forgiving disposition.
你这婊子
Cunt!
我现在看出来 你并不符合我的要求
I can now see you are not that.
我们的冒险之旅也该结束了
Our adventure is clearly over.
我给你订一张回伦敦的船票
I shall book you a passage back to London.
原来你身上
You had money...
其实一直都有钱吗
this whole time?
是古德的钱
It is God's money.
来应对突发事件
For emergencies.
突发事件已经持续他妈的好几周了
It has been a fucking emergency for weeks now!
我始终都相信
I believed in you the whole time...
你能迎难而上
that you would rise to the occasion.
但我错了 很显然 你的内心已经破裂了
But now I see that was a mistake, and there's clearly something broken in you.
我的内心都是被你破裂的
You broke that something in me!
我觉得这个对话只是在绕圈子
I feel this conversation has become circular.
婊子
Cunt!
斯瓦尼夫人 我考量了我的处境
Madam Swiney, I have examined my situation.
我需要性交和钱
I need sex and money.
我需要一个爱人
I could take a lover...
又一个像维德伯恩那样供养我的人
another Wedderburn who would keep me...
但那人必定要对我投入大量的关注
but may require an awful lot of attention.
或是一个只需陪伴二十分钟的爱人
Or else it's 20 minutes at a time...
这样我每天的剩余时间就可以好好研究这个世界
and the rest of my day is free to study on the world...
研究如何让这个世界变好
and the improvement of it.
因此我来到你这里
Hence, I seek employment...
这个霉味萦绕的处所求取一份工作 换取一份通奸的美好时光
at your musty-smelling establishment of good-time fornication.
一个规划自由之路的女人
A woman plotting her course to freedom.
真是讨人喜欢
How delightful.
跟我来
Come.
啊 是美味先生来了
Monsieur Saveur.
一块牛里脊
A filet mignon.
上等的牛肉
A prime cut.
她叫贝拉
Bella.
办完事说 了不起
Say "formidable" at the end.
是这里的规矩
House rules.
那是你身上的味道吗
Is that smell you?
了不起
Formidable.
去异味的
For the smell.
还有茶 不过只是因为这茶好喝
And tea. Just because tea is nice.
过程很粗暴
It was brutal...
但奇怪的是并不让我讨厌
in a strangely not unpleasant way.
拿着这个小册子
Pamphlet.
-读一读  -这是写什么的
- Read. - What is that?
一位想要改变世界的人
Une personne qui veut... change the world pour le meilleur.
让世界变得更好 变成美好的世界
Make it better. A better world.
我也是那样的人
Then I am that too.
斯瓦尼夫人
Madam Swiney...
我们这样一字排开等人挑选
this lineup system...
你不会真指望我去和一位我甚至都讨厌的男人上楼
you really expect me to go upstairs with a man even if I find him distasteful...
等他粗鲁地在我身上激烈跳跃后
and therefore am sad...
我为此感到难过吧
when I let him furious jump me?
规矩就是这样 亲爱的
That is the way it is, my darling.
天呐 你很漂亮
Gosh, you look pretty.
想想你是怎么接受被人蹂躏的
How it agrees with you to be ravaged.
倒是这样
I suppose so.
那么 你难道只顾自己喜好
So, would you not prefer it if the women chose...
而不愿意让女人来做选择吗
as it would be a sign of enthusiasm toward you?
你丝毫不会察觉到你在她们身上激烈跳跃后
You wouldn't have the vague sense that they are in a state of horror...
她们会感到害怕吗
when you jump them.
贝拉是新来这里的 可能脑子有点问题
Bella is new and may have a mental illness.
就像古德 我父亲说的那样
As God, my father, says...
新事物会代替现在的旧事物
it is only the way it is until we discover the new way it is...
然后更新的事物又会替代这之前的事物
and then that is the way it is until we discover the new way it is...
一直发展到这个世界不再单调
and so it goes until the world is no longer flat...
电力的出现照亮了夜空 鞋子也不再需要系带
electricity lights the night, and shoes are no longer tied with ribbons.
作为一名社会主义者 我完全同意你说的话
As a socialist, I agree entirely.
托妮特 你可真是长了张巧嘴
Toinette, you have such a clever mouth.
梅尔索先生可以去免费享受了
Monsieur Mersault will enjoy it for free.
现在就去
Go. Now.
贝拉 来一下我办公室
Bella, a moment in my office.
你的耳垂真是秀色可餐
You have the most delicious looking lobes.
谢谢
Thank you.
我必须
I must...
真是抱歉 我咬出血了
Oh, I am sorry. I drew blood.
给你
Here.
有时候我看到年轻漂亮的女孩 会放纵自己一下
I sometimes give in to myself when I see beauty, young beauty.
终将有一天 亲爱的
For one day, my dear...
你会变成一个满脸皱纹的老妇人
you will be a wrinkled, old husk.
到时候不论是花钱还是免费 都不会有人想要你
And no one will want you either to pay you for it or to have it for free.
我还是相信有选择权的人才会更快乐
I still believe everyone would be happier if we could choose.
你是个理想主义者
An idealist.
跟我一样
Like me.
多么讨人喜欢啊
How delightful you are.
但我们有时候也要向外界低头
But we must give in to the demands of the world sometimes.
努力应对困难 击败困难
Grapple with it, try to defeat it.
-所以你也相信我说的话吗  -当然
- So you believe as me? - Of course.
但有些男人就是享受和你做的时候你满脸不乐意
But some men enjoy that you do not like it.
什么
What?
那可真变态
- That is... - Sick.
但也是好商机
But good business.
跟我来
Come with me.
这是我的外孙女
My grandchild.
体弱多病 需要不停看病
Sick and poorly, and requiring much doctoring.
我要是给了你选择的权利 不但会殃及到我的生意
My choice of giving you choice will jeopardize the business.
还会危及到她的健康和性命
Her health. Her life.
-这是你想要的吗 贝拉  -当然不是
- Do you want that, Bella? - Of course not.
你真不想 你可太善良了
You don't? You're so lovely.
我还以为你又要咬我耳垂了
I thought you were going for my lobes.
我们必须去工作
We must work.
我们必须去赚钱
We must make money.
但除了这些 我们还必须去经历人生百味
But more than that, we must experience everything...
不只是好事
not just the good.
还有那些落魄 恐惧 悲伤
But degradation, horror, sadness...
这样我们才能完整 贝拉
This makes us whole, Bella.
这样我们才是有血有肉的人
Makes us people of substance...
不是轻狂天真 未被世俗沾染的孩子
not flighty, untouched children.
这样之后 才能了解世界
Then we can know the world.
而当我们了解了世界
And when we know the world...
世界便是我们的
the world is ours.
我想要这样
I want that.
这样的话
Now...
就去和别人上床
go and fuck someone...
然后带回来十法郎给我
and bring me 10 francs.
首先 我提议做一个小测验
First, I suggest a short quiz.
什么小测验
A quiz?
你给我讲一段童年的回忆
You tell me a childhood memory.
然后我给你讲一个笑话 敲敲
Then I tell a joke.
然后快快地闻一下薰衣草油
Then a quick sniff...
如果需要的话 再用它快速浸泡一下
and if necessary, a quick douse in lavender oil.
这些东西都会增强体验 让它变得妙极了
And all of this will enhance the experience making it formidable.
不 讲笑话是我来
Non, I tell the joke.
你负责讲你的回忆
You the memory.
你小的时候 在希腊 从自行车上摔下来了对吗
When you were little in Greece, you fell from your bicycle?
血 顺着我的腿淌下去
Blood. Down my leg.
快乐吗
Joy?
你看着血感觉很快乐
You watched the blood with joy.
敲敲
Knock, knock.
是谁在门口啊
Qui c'est?
是奶酪
Fromage.
请问奶酪您贵姓
Fromage qui?
很"奶酪"见到你
Cheese to meet you.
你知道的
You know it.
你闻起来不错
You smell okay.
我们做爱吧
Let us fuck.
古德给了你一份礼物 朋友
God gave you a gift, my friend.
剖得不够优雅
Very inelegant work.
你想家的时候就这么做吗
This is what you do when you're homesick?
你希望什么
You wish what?
孩子们到了受教育的年龄 性教育
My boys are of an age for education. Sexual.
我会来演示
I will demonstrate.
我明白了
I see.
有时
At times.
我该躺下 还是弯腰 还是跨骑呢
Shall I lay, bend, astride?
-我们从简单的开始吧  -好的
Let's start simple, please.
为了让事情顺利进行
To aid things along...
-要把一根手指插到屁股里  -不
- a finger in the arse. - No.
或者有点轻微的窒息感也可以
Or a slight choking may do it.
回家去吧
Go home!
贝拉
Bella!
斯瓦尼夫人说得对
Madam Swiney was right.
我正在挖掘自己未知的部分
I am discovering parts of myself hitherto unknown.
这么想也行吧
It is a way to look at it.
各种各样的欲望被揭露出来是很令人着迷的
The variety of desires being made manifest is fascinating.
你找到那个男的了吗
Have you had the man...
就是往你嘴里塞了一块菠萝 然后把你盖在尘土里那个
who puts a wedge of pineapple in your mouth and covers you in dust?
贝拉
Bella.
我几乎都准备好原谅你了
I'm almost ready to forgive you.
我已经订好了回家的铺位
I've booked our berths home...
让妈妈准备好我们的婚床了
and I've told Mother to prepare our wedding bed.
你上了那个手上插钩子的家伙吗
Did you fuck that guy with hooks for hands?
上了 我就知道
You did. I know!
我把那家伙狠揍了一顿
I beat the tar out of that guy.
邓肯 我以为你走了
Duncan. I thought you left.
我是走了 回到船上 但我开始疼痛和呕吐
Back to the ship, but started to ache and vomit...
所以我来这是来救你的
so I'm here to save you.
你好 邓肯
Hello, Duncan.
回家吧 邓肯
Go home, Duncan.
我们结束了
Our time has ended.
我看着你却毫无感觉
I look at you and feel nothing...
但我始终想不通的是 为什么之前会看上你
but the lingering question of how did I ever want you?
我们要去参加社会主义分子集会了
And we must go to the meeting of socialists.
你们这些妓女
You're whores.
我们是自己的生产资料
We are our own means of production.
快滚吧
Go away.
脚
Foot.
画 脚
Paint, foot.
非常好
Very good.
语言学习还是慢 但有在进步
Language is slow but improving.
画 脚
Paint. Foot.
天才
Genius.
您能不能别对她那么残忍
Can you not be so cruel to her?
我在贝拉身上犯了一个错误
I made a mistake with Bella.
我允许你有感情
I allowed feelings to develop.
但不准对她动情 她跟那些鸡狗没什么区别
There are none for her. She is no different to the chicken dog.
脚
Foot.
也许这样更好吧
It is better this way, perhaps...
这样我就能对父亲的冷漠有所理解
and gives some insight into my father's coolness to me.
这就是科学的必需选择
It was a necessity of science.
天啊 老兄
Good God, man.
-脚  -我不指望你能懂
- Foot. - I do not expect you to understand...
乡村医生
village doctor.
对了 我还要你给我做手术呢
By the way, I need you to operate on me.
我要给面目可憎的你安上一颗跳动的心脏吗
Shall I put a beating heart in your monstrous form?
如果你有空的话
If you have time...
可以在取出这个的同时
while taking...
给我装个心脏
this out.
我会把肿瘤周围的一些囊肿切掉
I'll remove some cysts from around the tumor.
不用了 你缝上就好
No need. You may close me up.
它已经扩散了 我看到有小息肉
It has spread. I see tiny polyps.
我快要死了
I am dying.
要怎么对病人开口呢 嗯
How to break it to the patient, eh?
巴克斯特
Baxter...
别对着伤口哭 你会害我因为败血症死得更快的
Do not cry into the wound! You'll kill me faster with sepsis.
安静下来
Quiet now.
然后帮我缝好
And close me up.
找到她
Find her.
我都关门了
I am closed.
热巧克力 亲爱的
Hot chocolate, my dear.
还有巧克力面包
And pain au chocolat.
你是我的最爱
You are my favorite.
我听你对别人也这么说
I have heard you say that to the others.
我们是你用赞美和巧克力浇灌的机器
We are a machine you feed with compliments and chocolate.
你们是我用爱浇灌的孩子
You are my children I feed with love.
不好的事发生了 斯瓦尼
Something terrible has happened, Swiney.
我几乎什么也感觉不到
I feel almost nothing.
我的同理心正在演变
My empathy is creeping toward what I would describe...
变成一种傲慢的愤怒
as contemptuous rage.
太棒了
This is fabulous.
是吗
It is?
你正处于黑暗时期
You're in the dark period.
在光明和智慧降临之前
Before light and wisdom come to you.
你必须坚持下去
You must forge through it...
一旦到达彼岸
and once on the other side...
你就会对这一刻充满感激 但你必须继续前行
you will be grateful to this moment, but you must keep going.
我懂
I see.
你有一个小伤疤
You've got a baby scar.
我的伤疤是和妈妈一起留下的
Mine is with ma maman.
我没有
I don't have one.
这是意外的伤疤
It is an accident scar.
但你不是第一个误会的
But you're not the first to have made the mistake.
为什么不说实话
Why lie?
我没有骗你
I'm not lying.
我的古德温亲口告诉我的
My Godwin told me himself.
维德伯恩
Wedderburn.
早上好 先生
Good day, sir.
你给古德温·巴克斯特写信
You wrote to Mr. Godwin Baxter.
他把一个无法无天的恶魔送到世上
He has sent a demon at large into the world.
恶魔存在于一个诱人且永不满足的身体中
The devil's wrapped in an alluring body that cannot be satiated...
她会一针一针将人拆解开来
and a mind that picks people apart stitch by stitch...
就像拆解一个被血染 烧焦的布娃娃 接着和大象的粪便一同排出
like a bloodied and burned rag doll shat out of an elephant's arse.
贝拉
Bella.
她在哪
Where is she?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是她未婚夫
I'm her fiancé, sir.
看得出来 你们结束得不太和平
Obviously, things did not end well between you.
不和平
Did not?
她毁了我
She destroyed me.
我们都要为自己的行为负责
Well, we're all masters of our own ship, sir.
话虽没错
There's that.
但我不喜欢你 也不喜欢你说的话
I do not like you or your words.
古德温·巴克斯特这混蛋
That Godwin Baxter.
他什么都知道 让贝拉找上了我
He knew, and he set her on to me.
他设计害我
He trapped me.
贝拉在哪
Where is she?
别跟我提她 我恨她入骨
Would not wish her on my worst enemy.
我能帮你解决她这个问题
I shall save you from her, sir.
请原谅我的失望之举 你就告诉我吧
Forgive my frustration. Just tell me.
你这一拳一点都不疼
It does not hurt.
我已经五脏俱焚
I have no insides.
她已把我掏空
She hollowed me out.
我的灵魂 我的积蓄 都空空如也
My soul. My bank account!
我只是一只蠹虫 一具空壳
I am a bug! A shell!
要不我们唱首歌
Shall we sing?
我们都是水手
Oh, we are sailors...
这一点
It doesn't...
一点也不疼
Doesn't hurt.
我也不想这样
I do not wish it to be like this.
是你逼我的
You force my hand.
我们要为自己的行为负责
"We're all masters of our own ship."
你这婊子养的混蛋傻逼
You cunting cunt-faced deadshit.
求你了
Please.
我已经在好言相问了
I ask you as politely as I can.
她在哪
Where is she?
伦敦
那婊子回来了
The whore is back.
古德
God?
贝拉
Bella!
马克斯给我写了信
Max wrote me.
-你病了  -我不是病了 我是要死了
- You are ill? - I am not. I am dying.
差别很细微 但我作为内科医生 很重视这一点
A subtle difference, but one I take seriously as a physician.
你能来我心情就很好了
You are a sight and a good one.
你不能死
You cannot die.
经验证明 我会死的
Empirical data says different.
我好想你
I missed you.
现在我得躺下了
I now have to lie down.
我也不只是要带来好心情
It is not all sunshine I bring.
还要直视你的双眼 问一些难回答的问题
I also bring beady eyes and hard questions.
我身体里是有一个孩子吗
Did I have a baby in me?
如果是的话 孩子在哪
And if so, where is it?
我明白了
I see.
严格来说 你就是那个孩子
Well, technically, you are your baby.
而且这样说来 你也既是你的母亲
And also, I suppose you are your mother.
但又不是
And also neither.
记忆被抹除
No memory survives.
经历也不复存在
No experiences survive.
什么叫我既是母亲又是孩子
What do you mean I am mother and daughter?
你什么都知道 却什么都不说
You knew and did not tell.
我当时觉得没必要
I did not see good reason to.
而且我太懦弱了
And were too cowardly to.
这也是一个原因
A bit of that as well.
我想要陪在你身边
I wanted to be with you...
而且我也不确定 你会不会理解这一切
and I was not sure you would even understand.
而且巴克斯特控制欲也很强
And Baxter kind of makes one a prisoner to him.
而且 我
And I am...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
砰
Bam.
她是谁
Who is this?
婊子贝拉
Bell whore
-婊子贝拉  -看来你已经介绍过我了 普瑞姆女士
- Bell whore - I see you've introduced me then, Prim.
-但我挺喜欢她的  -婊子贝拉
- I like this one though. - Bell whore
-够了 费利西蒂  -婊子
- That's enough now, Felicity... - Bell whore
操
Fucker.
又一个
Another one?
我们想你了
We missed you.
怪物
Monsters.
操他妈的
Oh, fucking hell.
婊子
Bell whore
如果一个人已经承受着痛苦 那么我想打他
It is hard to be in the position where one wants to hit someone...
这有点不方便下手
who is already in obvious pain.
确实是个难题
It is a conundrum for sure.
那你宁愿是一团鼻子上有鱼钩的灰色肉块吗
Would you rather be a gray slab of flesh with a fishhook in your nose?
但是之后很长时间都觉得很糟糕
I will feel good for a second, but bad for longer, so...
我鼻子上真有个鱼钩吗
I really had a fishhook in my nose?
是的
You did.
所以我是你的创造
So, I am your creation...
她也是
as is the other one.
你们都不是创作
Neither of you are that.
她拿着一把锤子 唱着歌 游荡在走廊里
She wanders the halls with a hammer and a song...
那不是我的过错
and that is not my doing.
我读了你寄回家的贺卡和信件
And I read your cards and letters home...
看着你无畏地创造了贝拉·巴克斯特 这是一个奇迹
and watched you fearlessly create Bella Baxter with wonder.
我觉得活着很好 所以我原谅你
I am finding being alive fascinating, so I'll forgive you the act...
不过你欺骗并囚禁我 我依然恨你
but always hate the lies and trapping that followed.
明白了
Understood.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
我也是
You too.
我置愤怒 困惑 和大脑中不和谐的声音于不顾 我很想你
Anger, confusion, and brain dissonance aside, I missed you.
我回到家 闻到甲醛味
I arrived home, and I smelled the formaldehyde...
我就知道接下来要干什么
and I knew what is next.
我要成为一名医生
I will be a doctor.
我的手术任凭你安排
My surgery is yours.
我的父亲曾告诉我
My father once told me...
下刀要怀有同情心
always carve with compassion.
他他妈是个蠢货
He was a fucking idiot.
不过这意见不坏
But it's not bad advice.
他也没多长时间活了
He does not have long.
我知道
I know.
你怎么对我们的婚约只字不提
You've not mentioned our betrothal.
你那时还年轻
You were much younger.
没什么束缚
There is no bind.
我对你着迷 而巴克斯特利用了我
I was mesmerized by you, and Baxter took advantage.
所以你不再喜欢我了
So, you are mesmerized no more?
我依然着迷
I am still mesmerized.
我曾是一个妓女 你明白吗
I've been a whore, you understand?
-嗯  -为了金钱 我让男人进入我的身体
Cocks for money inside me.
你对这件事没意见吗
You okay with that?
我卖淫这件事会不会
Does the whoring thing challenge the desire...
考验你心中男人固有的占有欲
for ownership that men have?
维德伯恩知道我在卖淫时
Wedderburn became much weepy and sweary...
又哭又骂
when he discovered my whoring.
我只是嫉妒那些男人能陪伴你
I find myself merely jealous of the men's time with you...
我对你没有任何道德上的谴责
rather than any moral aspersion against you.
这是你的身体 贝拉·巴克斯特
It is your body, Bella Baxter.
你可以随意支配
Yours to give freely.
我一般要30法郎
I generally charged 30 francs.
听起来不多
Well, that seems low.
你相信人们能进步吗 马克斯
Do you believe people improvable, Max?
我相信
I do.
就像身体的疾病可以被治愈一样
Just as a human body can be cured of illness...
人们也可以在一些方面进步
so can men and women be cured of aspect.
你愿意娶我吗 马克斯·麦克坎多斯
Will you marry me, Max McCandles?
我愿意
I will.
以后你可以少说点话
We will need less of your tongue in the future...
不过总体来说 我们相处得很好
but overall, most agreeable.
我记住了
I will take that note.
你体检过吗
And have you been checked for disease?
还没有 不过我会去的
I have not, but I shall.
我很享受我们之间这种实际的爱情
I'm enjoying this practical love we have.
我向你保证 我的爱也充满了激情
But I assure you mine is also passionate.
你真可爱
You are adorable.
你一直很可爱
You always were.
古德 你居然走路了
God, you are walking.
我因为脚趾疼注射了五毫克海洛因
I have taken five milligrams of heroin through the toes for pain...
吃了点安非他命提神
amphetamines for energy...
还有可卡因 因为我喜欢可卡因
and cocaine because I am partial to cocaine.
我来陪你走向圣坛
I've come here to walk you down the aisle.
根据教会赋予我的权力
And so, by the powers vested in me by the church...
我在此宣告两人的结合
I shall solemnize this union.
贝拉·巴克斯特 你是否接受这个男人成为你的丈夫
Do you, Bella Baxter, take this man as your husband?
我们是不是忘了问有没有人反对
Did we miss the part about anyone objecting to this?
还是因为教理问答的伪现代化改造 导致这部分被删掉了
Or has that been removed in some kind of faux modernization of the catechism?
你好 维多利亚
Hello, Victoria.
你看起来很不错
You look well.
你是说我吗 先生
Do you refer to me, sir?
男人通常不会向妻子做自我介绍
A man doesn't normally introduce himself to his wife.
如果我必须介绍的话
But if I must...
他是幕后主使古德
He is the God of it.
我不知道是他控制了她 还是她控制了他
I do not know if he's in her power or she in his.
这是魔鬼的杰作 看啊
'Tis Devil's work at hand. Look!
他咳出的不是空气 而是血
He coughs not air as a normal man but blood.
他得癌症了 你个白痴
He has cancer, you fucking idiot.
邓肯
Duncan.
不要盯着我看 恶魔
Do not lay your eyes on me, demon!
正如我所说 我是阿尔弗雷德·布莱辛顿将军
As I was saying, General Alfred Blessington.
你叫我阿尔菲
"Alfie" to you.
你真的不记得我吗
You really do not know me?
维德伯恩先生把你的照片刊登在报纸上的时候
When Mr. Wedderburn put your photo in the paper...
我记起旅馆那个老太婆叫你维多利亚·布莱辛顿
I remembered that old bird in the hotel called you Victoria Blessington...
我便拼凑出了这幅邪恶的拼图
and I pieced this diabolical fuckfest of a puzzle together.
-你是  -你亲爱的阿尔菲
- You are... - Your dear Alfie.
你离开的时候 因为怀孕 既焦虑又歇斯底里
You left in a state of some mental addlement and hysteria over your pregnancy.
我发现你离开后 感觉被开膛破肚了
On the discovery of your absence, I felt disemboweled.
我曾在战场上把人开膛破肚
I have disemboweled men on the field of battle...
想象那会是一种沉闷又空洞的疼痛
and I always imagined a dull, hollow throbbing...
我当时就是这种感觉
and that is what it was like.
尸体还会散发恶臭 但在这里不适合用作比喻
There's also a stench, but that does not apply as a metaphor here.
我找到你了 亲爱的
But here you are, my darling.
我找到你了
Here you are.
天呐
God.
我不记得你了
I have no recollection of you.
我是贝拉·巴克斯特
I am Bella Baxter.
太伤人了
Hurtful.
或许是你撞到了头
But perhaps you've hit your head...
这些人便利用了你
and these men have clearly taken advantage of you.
请你离开 先生
Please go, sir.
-你以前是我的丈夫吗  -我是你亲爱的阿尔菲
- You were my husband? - Your dear Alfie.
贝拉 我很抱歉
Bella, I'm sorry.
我想离开了
Actually, I would like to go.
-什么  -贝拉
What?
Bella?
-你有马车吗  -先生
You have a carriage, sir?
有
Yes.
我们走吧
Let us go then.
贝拉
Bella!
让我走吧 古德
Let me go, God.
马克斯 你不要阻止我
Max, you will not stop me.
你能回来简直太好了 维多利亚
It is good to have you back, Victoria.
我和仆人们关系不太好
The servants and I have not been getting along.
我担心他们会造反
I fear an uprising.
记得大卫吗 亲爱的
You remember David, darling?
阿丽森 看看谁回来了
Allison, look who's back.
你认识我吗
You know me?
跟我讲讲我自己
Tell me about myself.
我待人友善吗
Was I nice?
吃吧
Eat.
都是你喜欢的
All your favorites.
熏鱼 鹅肉
Kippers, goose...
牛舌 香槟
tongue, champagne.
我很想你
I've missed you.
婚姻不幸的根源是什么
What was the root of the unhappiness?
她为什么要从桥上跳下去
What drove her to leap off the bridge?
你讨厌那个小孩
You hated the baby.
你叫它怪物
You called it "the monster."
我明白了
I see.
我已经意识到我缺少母性的本能
I have noticed a lack of maternal instinct.
但我还是很高兴你能回家
And yet I'm happy to have you home.
我们是怎么认识的来着
How did we meet?
在舞会上
At a ball.
那我们为什么喜欢对方呢
Why did we like each other?
我们都喜欢找乐子
We shared a love of good times.
看着
Watch.
阿丽森 上汤
Allison, soup!
雷克斯
Rex!
-该死
Fuck!
阿丽森
Allison...
等你清洁好了 我们要吃奶酪
we'll have some cheese when you can.
-我们喜欢对人残忍吗  -嗯
A love of cruelty?
看来 我不是一个善良的人
- I was not a kind person, it seems. - Kind?
善良 你可没这么无聊维多利亚
You would never be so dull, Victoria.
这想法太糟糕了
Appalling idea.
维德伯恩说你当过妓女
Wedderburn says you were a whore.
-我觉得那有点  -我是当过
- I suspect that was part... - I was.
在巴黎的时候
In Paris.
现在我厌倦了 但是那段时光很有意思
I tired of it, but it was fascinating.
-好吧  -这些熏鱼有点怪 但是挺好吃的
- Right. - These kippers are strangely delicious.
放了醋或者别的什么
Vinegary or something.
婚姻会带来持续的挑战
Marriage is a constant challenge.
有些问题我们能解决 而有些我们不得不妥协
Some, we bend to, some we bend to us.
我会尽力原谅你卖淫的事
I will try to forgive you for the whoring.
你在性爱方面的疯狂总是一发不可收拾
Your sexual hysteria was often out of hand.
我也会尽力原谅你杀死了我们尚未出生的孩子
And for the killing of our unborn child.
说实话 要是我把你对不起我的事一一列举出来
In fact, when I list the ways you've wronged me...
耶稣基督他本人 都会亲自用球棒敲你的脑袋
Jesus Christ himself would probably beat your head in with a bat.
有一个宽容的丈夫是你的福气
You're blessed with a forgiving husband.
我可没有对不起你 阿尔菲
I've not wronged you, Alfie...
因为我根本不认识你
as I do not know you.
你很幸运 因为我在失忆症领域经验丰富
Well, you're in luck as I've had a lot of experience in the field with amnesia.
我认识那些想忘记自己曾身处战场的人
Either men who wish to forget where they were...
还有人想忘记如钟声般
or a mortar exploded nearby...
在头盖骨内鸣响的迫击炮声
ringing their cranium like a church bell.
我建议我们在房子这里待几个月
I suggest we stick close to the house for several months...
或者待一年
maybe a year.
直到你完全康复为止
Until you've made a full recovery.
我想走就走 但是你想困住我 真是让我受宠若惊
I will leave at my leisure, but I am flattered by your desire to trap me.
你可不是第一个这么做的人
You're not the first.
亲爱的 你要是想走的话
I will have to shoot you in the fucking head...
我他妈会一枪打在你的头上
if you try to leave, darling.
从前面打还是从后面打
The front or the back of the head?
后面
The back.
这样才能确认你是真的要走
As to be sure you were leaving...
而我没有草率行事
and I was not being rash.
我好想你
I have missed you.
所以 我是囚犯了
So, I'm a prisoner?
这次谈话的走向 令人遗憾
This conversation has gone down an unfortunate route.
我确信你会和以前一样快乐
I am sure you will be as happy as you were before.
像我从桥上跳下来之前一样快乐吗
As I was before when I threw myself from a bridge?
我觉得你是找鱼的时候摔下去的
I suspect you fell while looking for fish.
你为什么要违背我的意愿 把我留在这里呢
Why would you want to keep me here if I do not wish to stay?
要是一定要溺死 就溺死在爱河里吧
If one must drown, let it be in the river of love.
大卫
David...
这只野鸡难道吃完了吗
does that pheasant look stripped to the bone?
先生 我看错了
It was a misjudgment, sir.
对不起
I apologize.
亲爱的 要吃甜点吗
Dessert, darling?
容易弄下来吗
It comes off easy?
就像摘下西装扣子一样简单
Like a button on a suit.
我在非洲见过他们用磨尖的石头做这个
I saw them do it in Africa with sharpened rocks...
但是我自己做了一个精度更高的版本
but had my own more precise device made.
你是只想割阴蒂包皮
Do you want just clitoral hood...
还是连阴蒂头也一起
or glans as well?
把她邪恶的阴部全割下来
The whole infernal packet.
能让她永远安分下来
It will calm her no end.
这次我们会成功的
This time we will get it done.
我会先给她打镇定剂 然后今晚带她去你的手术室
I shall get her sedated and bring her to your surgery this evening.
维多利亚 亲爱的
Victoria, darling!
你在哪
Where are you?
时机刚好
Perfect timing.
来杯马蒂尼
Martini.
还是不了
Rather not.
不过 我想我还是想离开这
I would, however, like to leave.
我认为我们一起的时光是有趣的
I have found our time together interesting...
但我明白我为什么会跳桥了
but I've ascertained why I jumped from a bridge.
我希望去看看古德 他快不行了
I wish to go see my near dead God.
不错的想法
Adorable idea.
不幸的是 亲爱的
Unfortunately, my darling...
我的一生都致力于侵占土地
my life is dedicated to the taking of territory.
而你是我的
You are mine...
我言尽于此
and that is the long and short of it.
我不是领土
I am not territory.
问题的根源就在你两腿之间
The root of the problem is between your legs.
我会彻底解决它
I will have it off...
让它不会使你分心也不会使你变心
and it will not distract and divert you anymore.
你看 一个男人穷尽一生 和他的性冲动纠缠
You see, a man spends his life wrangling his sexual compulsions.
这是种诅咒 但 某种层面上也是他一生的事业
It's a curse and yet, in some ways, his life's work.
女人一生的事业是孩子
A woman's life's work is children.
我打算摆脱你两腿间那个邪恶的东西
I intend to rid you of that infernal packet between your legs...
并且直接在你身体里埋一颗种子
and plant a seed in you straight after.
我来解释下发生了什么
Let me explain what has happened.
维多利亚 你的妻子 从桥上跳下去淹死了
Victoria, your wife, threw herself from a bridge and died.
古德温·巴克斯特发现了她 把她带回了手术室
Godwin Baxter found her, brought her to his surgery.
他摘出了她怀着的婴儿 取出了婴儿的大脑
He then removed the baby, removed the brain from the baby...
将婴儿大脑移植回了这具身体并重塑了我
transplanted it into my head and reanimated me.
我会给你带手术档案的 听起来很迷人啊
I'll bring you the file. It's actually quite fascinating.
总之 我要保留我的新人生
However, I will keep my new life...
以及我可爱的旧阴蒂 谢谢
and my lovely old clitoris, thank you.
请你为我叫一辆马车
If you'd call a carriage for me.
他们聊了又聊
They talk and talk...
然后在某一刻 除了拔枪无话可说
and yet at some point there's nothing left but to pull a gun.
这就是对女人的方式
'Tis the way with women.
你屈服了吗
Are you giving in?
我宁愿你给我的心脏来一枪也不会屈服
I'd rather you shot me in the fucking heart.
如果我不得不的话我会做的
I will oblige if I have to.
喝了这杯 亲爱的
Drink the drink, darling.
金酒和麻醉剂
Chloroform and gin.
某种层面上说 摆脱不断追寻的自我 是一种解脱
In some ways it would be a relief to be rid of my questing self.
喝了这杯 自由就是你的了
Sip deeply and that freedom is yours.
妈的
Fuck.
马克斯
Max?
马克斯 我们必须得带他去做手术
Max. We have to get him to surgery.
否则他会死的
He'll die if we don't.
他出血好多
Bleeding a lot.
你他妈死定了
You're fucking dead.
贝拉 如果他活着
Bella, if he lives...
我觉得他不会善罢甘休的
I do not sense he is a man who will stop.
我不能看着他失血而死
Well, I won't watch him bleed to death.
但我同意 他有进步空间
But I agree, he could do with improvement.
我已经摘除了子弹 也止血了
I've removed the bullet and stopped the bleeding.
我拿来了笔记
I have the notes.
我在这儿比在其他地方都要开心
I am never happier than when I'm in here.
贝拉
Bella.
你回来了
You're back.
那只是别人的故事
It was just a story of someone else...
不是贝拉·巴克斯特的故事
not Bella Baxter.
我的一生中 人们看我的眼神都充满了
All my life, people's eyes looked at me...
恐惧 怜悯
horror, pity...
但你
but you.
我们经历的一切
It's all very interesting...
都是那么有趣
what is happening.
解剖学考试让我很紧张
Anatomy exam is making me nervous.
我给你测试过很多次了 你没问题的
I've tested you many times. You know it.
没人比你更了解解剖了
No one knows anatomy better than you.
女士们 金酒喝吗
Ladies, gin?
当然
Please.
金酒
Gin?
我们应该给将军拿点水
We should get some water for the general.
本字幕由CSEG克隆字幕提取组提取分享  仅供学习交流之用  禁止压制  禁止删除字幕组及CSEG署名
费利西蒂
Felicity...
拿点水来
water.
字幕错漏、合作联系、加入我们，请发送邮件至：csegkelongzimutiquzu@gmail.com
欢迎关注新浪微博、微信公众号：CSEG克隆字幕提取组
可怜的东西